Chad Gullickson

3042 Pennsylvania Ave S Saint Louis Park, MN 55426 | 507-382-8992 | chadmgullickson@gmail.com

Professional Summary:

A four-year information technology professional with extensive experience as a web and application developer for many projects within the healthcare industry. Broadly and deeply knowledgeable in a wide variety of computer languages as well as the principles and techniques of website development and maintenance. Trained in Agile/Scrum for multiple projects with a variety of technologies used to better enhance systems for clients and end users.

Professional Experience:

Optum, Eden Prairie, MN

June 2014 - Present

Senior Application Developer

- Developed a mapping web application using ArcGIS and AngularJS
- Managed code repository and handled front end deployments
- Documented and fixed critical bugs from QA
- Set coding standards for front end

Web Application Developer

- Worked on multiple projects using different technologies like AngularJS, .NET, and Java
- Managed development time between different projects at a time
- Developed both client-side and back end API

Java Web Developer

- Used Agile/Scrum to develop a website to manage insurance claims
- Developed website using Java and Groovy with Spring
- Redeveloped front end of a project into a single page app using AngularJS

Ruby on Rails Web Developer

- Used Agile to develop startup websites in Ruby on Rails
- Enhance and developed automated provisioning of new laptops for employees
- Tracked and managed stories and tasks from entrepreneur

Meditech, Minnetonka, MN

February 2014 – June 2014

SQL Developer

- Optimized and developed stored procedures for hospitals to run to generate reports
- Maintained database and users' security clearance
- Complied with government standards for medical report generation

PC's For People, Mankato, MN

August 2012 - January 2013

Computer Technician

- Refurbished donated computers from corporations or individuals and distributed them to families and individuals in need
- Diagnosed and repaired hardware or software issues in computers of individuals that were receiving government assistance
- Worked with multiple software platforms and operating systems

Education:

Minnesota State University, Mankato

Master of Science – Information Technology

• APP: Automated Employee Scheduling System using Fuzzy Logic

Bachelor of Science – Information Technology, Magna Cum Laude

Technical Skills

JavaScript, AngularJS, MEAN stack, ArcGIS, HTML, CSS, Oracle SQL, SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MySQL, PL/SQL, Docker, Ruby on Rails, Java, .NET, Python, LAMP, Agile/Scrum, Data Analysis